# Jiajun Wu

Phone: +86 17362995517 Email: jjwu@connect.hku.hk

Address: CB, Main Campus, HKU, Hong Kong My GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/MaxwellWjj">https://github.com/MaxwellWjj</a>

Jiajun Wu is a PhD student in the Department of Electrical and Electronic Engineering, The University of Hong Kong. His research interests include hardware accelerator, neuromorphic computing, and computer architecture.



#### - EDUCATION -

#### THE UNIVERSITY OF HONG KONG

Hong Kong

PhD Student in Electrical and Electronic Engineering, from 09/2021 to present

Supervisor: Prof. Hayden Kwok-Hay So

Current Research Topics:

- AI Hardware Accelerator

- Computer Architecture

# HUAZHONG UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY

("Double First-Class" initiative, "985" Project)

Wuhan, China

Bachelor in IC Design and Integrated System, from 09/2017 to 06/2021 GPA 3.89/4.0

Supervisor: Prof. Chao Wang Representative Courses:

- CMOS Analog Integrated Circuit
- Fundamentals of Digital Integrated Circuit
- Hardware Description Language and Design of Digital System
- Processor Architecture
- Principles of Embedded System
- Principles of Computer Architecture

### **EXCHANGE & INTERNSHIP**

#### SINGAPORE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY AND DESIGN

Singapore

**Internship**, from 15/01/2020 to 03/02/2020

Supervised by Prof. Shaowei Lin, Singapore University of Technology and Design

Project: Study of Advanced Algorithms of Neuromorphic Computing and Hardware Implementation

#### ZHUHAI UM SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY RESEARCH INSTITUTE / UNIVERSITY OF MACAU

Zhuhai, China

**Internship**, from 28/07/2020 to 31/10/2020

Supervised by Prof. Sai Weng Sin, University of Macau

Project: Study of 3D ToF sensor based advanced mixed-signal circuit design

#### PUBLICATIONS -

**Jiajun Wu** *et al.*, "An Energy-Efficient GALS Multi-core Restricted Boltzmann Machine Processor with On-chip Bi-plausible Learning and Reconfigurable Sparsity", in *IEEE A-SSCC 2020*, Nov. 2020.

**Jiajun Wu**, Yi Zhan *et al.*, "Efficient Design of Spiking Neural Network With STDP Learning Based on Fast CORDIC," in *IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems I: Regular Papers*, vol. 68, no. 6, pp. 2522-2534, June 2021.

**Jiajun Wu** *et al.*, "An Energy-efficient Deep Belief Network Processor Based on Heterogeneous Multi-core Architecture with Transposable Memory and On-chip Learning," in *IEEE JETCAS*, under review.

#### ACADEMIC CAPABILITY =

- TOEFL iBT Reading-26; Listening-24; Speaking-22; Writing-23; Total-95 (21th, Dec 2019)
- Chinese invention patents:

CN110208702A, **Jiajun Wu**, Jinyang Wu et. al.

CN110118943A, Jinyang, Wu, Jiajun Wu et. al.

CN110118938A, Chuqi Jin, Jinyang Wu, Jiajun Wu et. al.

#### **SCHOLARSHIP** -

- Scholarship for Scientific and Technological Innovation (2018 & 2019) Huazhona University of Science and Technology

About 5% out of 600

- Scholarship for Merit Student (2019) Huazhong University of Science and Technology About 5% out of 600

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

#### STUDY OF TOF ALGORITHM BASED ADVANCED MIXED-SIGNAL CIS DESIGN

Zhuhai, China

Adviser: Prof. Sai Weng Sin Institution: Singapore University of Technology and Design July 2020 - present

The project is still going on. We are studying advanced recognition / classification algorithm based on Time-of-Flight (ToF) sensors and 3D images. Then, we look forward to implementing some energy-efficient accelerator such as NN accelerator, and finally getting a chip design.

## STUDY OF NEURAL NETWORK BASED NEUROMORPHIC COMPUTING AND HIGH ENERGY EFFICIENT **CHIP DESIGN**

Wuhan, China

Adviser: Prof. Chao Wang Institution: Research Lab of Ultra Low-Power and Intelligent Integrated Circuits May 2019 - present

Proposed a reconfigurable and highly efficient Spiking Neural Network (SNN) based on fast-convergence COordinate Rotation DIgital Computer (CORDIC) algorithm is proposed to achieve digital hardware implementation. This work has been summarized into a paper and under review.

# STUDY OF ADVANCED ALGORITHMS OF NEUROMORPHIC COMPUTING AND HARDWARE **IMPLEMENTATION**

Singapore

Adviser: Prof. Shaowei Lin Institution: Singapore University of Technology and Design Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

Joined the development of VPF and MPN source code and understood its mathematical significance deeply. Implemented basic modules of VPF algorithm's hardware accelerator and verified in RTL simulation level.

# HIGH RELIABILITY LITHIUM BATTERY SYSTEM WITH INTEGRATED ULTRASONIC SENSOR **NETWORK**

Wuhan, China

Adviser: Prof. Yue Shen

Institution: HUST-WISCO Joint Laboratory

Feb 2019 - May 2019

Integrated the ultrasonic sensor network into the battery module, using the ultrasonic signal to monitor the state of the battery, obtaining a high-precision state of charge and health, especially the battery gas detection limit is as low as 20 uL, far beyond traditional technology.

# COMPETITION AWARDS1 -

### FIRST PRIZE IN TI CUP COLLEGE STUDENTS' ELECTRONIC DESIGN COMPETITION

Institution: Science & Technology Innovation Center, HUST

Aug 2018

# SECOND PRIZE IN CHALLENGE CUP HUBEI PROVINCE COLLEGE STUDENTS' EXTRACURRICULAR ACADEMIC SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY WORKS CONTEST

Institution: School of Artificial Intelligence and Automation, HUST

Mar 2019 - May 2019

#### SECOND PRIZE IN CHINA UNIVERSITY INTELLIGENT ROBOT CREATIVE COMPETITION

Institution: School of Artificial Intelligence and Automation, HUST

Mar 2019 - May 2019

#### SKILLS -

#### MATLAB Verilog-HDL Embedded System C/C++ Pvthon FPGA

- Developed some small software apps based on Qt platform, such as hosts based on TCP or UART protocol.
- Finished some software/hardware co-design based on FPGA, especially with Xilinx's Zynq devices, such as digital oscilloscope, digital adaptive filter, communication systems, embedded system UI and so on.
- All the source codes are shared in my GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/MaxwellWjj">https://github.com/MaxwellWjj</a>

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup> Only national or provincial high-level competition awards are listed here.